Hello English learners, welcome back to
English Pod, my name is Marco and I'm Erica.
And today we have a fun and scary dialogue.
That's right, this
lesson is full of language
you can use to talk
about being scared.
Alright, so we're going to be looking at a
scary lesson today and we have nothing to
preview, so let's listen to this dialogue
and see why everyone is so scared.
Why are we at this
scary looking mansion?
It's like ultra-spooky. I
told you already Shabby,
the owner of the house
says there's a ghost hunting
his house, so we have
to go in and investigate.
I don't like this. Come on guys, stopping
such cowards, it's a mystery and adventure.
This place gives me the
creeps. Seriously guys,
let's get out of here.
I'm getting goosebumps
just being here.
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
That one came from this room.
Let's go and check it out.
What a ghost run!
Well, that sounds
really scary, but actually
it kind of reminds me
of another TV show.
Very similar to another
TV show, but it's different.
Okay, but some interesting
language that you
can use to talk about
things that are scary,
so why don't we look at that
now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
So let's start with the very
first line of our dialogue.
Shabby described the
mansion to be ultra-spooky.
It's ultra-spooky. Spooky.
So, okay, we've got two
interesting words here,
ultra and spooky. Now
spooky is scary, right?
It's a little bit scary. It
maybe makes you feel
a little bit uncomfortable or maybe
it makes you feel a little bit scared.
Okay, so not very scared.
Not super scared. But ultra-spooky.
So ultra is another way of saying
super or very or really spooky.
So if it's ultra-spooky
then it's very scary.
Okay. All right, so our
next word, they said that
in the house there is a
ghost haunting the house.
Okay, there is a ghost
haunting his house.
Okay, so the verb too
haunt. Okay, too haunt.
So the ghost is coming to the house
frequently and not letting them live in peace.
When a ghost haunts something
it visits it often and scares it.
Exactly. Now they
were all afraid and they
didn't want to go in and
so Wilma called everyone
cowards. Stop being
such cowards. Cowards.
So a coward. A coward is
a person that's not brave.
A person who's scared
of everything. My exactly.
So they were being
cowards. They were afraid
so that's why they
didn't want to go in.
Well speaking of being afraid,
Shabby said I'm getting goosebumps.
Goosebumps. To get goosebumps.
All right, to get goosebumps.
Now goosebumps, it may
sound a little bit
strange but it's very
easy when you're scared
or maybe you're cold.
The skin on your arms
or on your back gets a
little bit bumpy. So your
skin looks like chicken skin.
Exactly, chicken skin.
And that's actually
how we call it in
Spanish chicken skin but
this is goosebumps. So I guess it's
kind of similar. A goose? Yeah, same idea.
Goosebumps. All
right, and finally, Scruffy
said Shabby is a
scaredy cat. A scaredy cat.
You're a scaredy cat. Well, a scaredy
cat is not really a cat, right? No, no, no.
It's a person who's afraid of everything.
Similar to a coward. But more informal.
More much more informal
so somebody is a scaredy cat.
And I think even a little
bit more juvenile as adults.
Children use it. Yeah, as adults
you wouldn't say he's a scaredy cat.
All right, great. So some
interesting scary language.
I think we need to hear it one more
time slowed down in the dialogue.
Hey, why are we at the scary
looking mansion? It's like ultra spooky.
I told you already,
Shabby. The owner of the
house since there's a
ghost haunting his house.
So we have to go in and investigate.
I don't like this.
Come on, guys. Stop being such cowards.
It's a mystery and an adventure.
This place gives me the
creeps. Seriously, guys,
let's get out of here.
I'm getting goosebumps
just being here.
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
That left came from this
room. Let's go and check it out.
Look, a ghost run. Okay.
So now that we understand
that all the vocabulary we saw in language
takeaway, why don't we take a look at two
phrases now in fluency
builder? Fluency builder.
Well, Shabby said, we're at this scary
looking mansion. Scary looking mansion.
So a scary looking mansion.
Okay, so the mansion looks scary.
All right, so a mansion
is a big house, right?
That looks very scary.
Now, this is a really useful and
helpful pattern you can use with English.
Something looking.
So adjective looking. Right,
so you can say good looking.
Mm-hmm. And there's lots of examples.
So why don't we hear a few more now?
Example one. That guy is making me nervous.
He's really creepy looking.
Example two. I saw the craziest looking
house today. It was built upside down.
Example three.
What a nice looking dog. Can I pet him?
All right, great examples.
And now we know how
we can combine looking
with different adjectives.
Our next phrase, Shabby said,
this place gives me the creeps.
All right, gives me the creeps.
To give someone the
creeps. So if something gives
you the creeps, it makes you
feel uncomfortable and scared.
Maybe scared. Maybe
nervous. Mm-hmm.
Okay, so why don't we give
some examples? I could say,
hey, Marcos, see
that guy over there?
He keeps looking at me.
He's giving me the creeps.
Okay. All right, can say
clowns give me the creeps.
Oh, that's right.
You're afraid of clowns.
I am afraid of clowns. Okay.
Give me the creeps. All
right. Well, it's a really helpful,
useful phrase to use when
you're talking about being afraid.
Now, why don't we listen to
the dialogue one final time.
Eddie, why are we at
this guy looking mansion?
It's like ultra-spooky. I
told you already, Shabby.
The owner of the house
says there's a ghost hunting
his house, so we have
to go in and investigate.
I don't like this.
Come on, guys.
Stop being such cowards.
It's a mystery and adventure.
This place gives me the
creeps. Seriously, guys,
let's get out of here.
I'm getting goosebumps
just being here.
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
That one came from this room.
Let's go and check it out.
Look, a ghost run.
Okay, so an interesting
dialogue about ghosts
and haunted houses. So
what do you think, Erica?
Do you believe in ghosts?
Have you ever seen a ghost?
No, I totally do not believe in ghosts,
but I understand that you disagree with me.
Well, I've experienced
strange things, but I
don't know if it was a ghost
or an alien. I don't know.
Could have been anything. An alien. An
invisible alien. Okay, so what happened?
Well, once I was having
dinner with my parents,
and we had a table and on top of
the table, there was a glass full of water.
And all of a sudden it started
to move across the table,
and then it started
to spin while it moved.
So was there an earthquake
or something happening?
No, nothing. We were
just the only thing in the
whole table that was
moving was that, and we all
just kind of stared at
the glass moving, and we
didn't know what to do.
And then my mom started
kind of giggling a nervous laugh, and
we really didn't know what happened.
No, I understand that in Latin America,
people are more superstitious. They're more,
they believe more in ghosts, right?
Exactly. In Latin America,
people are very superstitious.
They believe in ghosts or in spirits, or
we have a lot of urban legends about, you
know, like a leprechaun
that lives under a bridge,
or you know, somebody's
grandma that comes
and haunts them, or
visits them at night and
stuff like that. So
yeah, Latin American
people are very
superstitious in this sense.
Yeah, I think in Anglo
countries, it's a little
bit less common to say
that you believe in ghosts.
Like maybe inside you,
you think ghosts are
true, but you wouldn't
really tell people that.
Right. I think the difference would be that
you have a different type of superstition,
like people are afraid of black
cats or the floor or the number 13.
Yeah. Or opening your umbrella in a house.
Exactly. Yeah. So because they consider it
to be bad luck, but not because something
like a ghost or an alien is
going to come out and eat them.
So listeners, why don't you tell
us what you think about ghosts?
Are people superstitious
in your country?
Did they believe in ghosts?
Come to our website,
englishpot.com and let us know.
And we'll see you guys there.
Well, thanks for downloading and goodbye.